logi.com 2016-06-20

# YOUR PRIVACY & SECURITY

IE8/IE9/IE10 is no longer a supported browser. Please use a more current browser to view our site.

As your privacy is important to us, Logitech has prepared this Statement of Privacy and Security (“Statement”) so that you may better understand how Logitech uses and protects the personal information collected on its website [www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/) (“Site”). Please take the time to review this page and contact us at [support.logitech.com/response-center](http://support.logitech.com/response-center) with any questions or concerns.

COLLECTION OF INFORMATION  
HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION   
CONTROL & REVIEW OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION  
PROTECTION OF INFORMATION  
CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT  
COOKIES

#### COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

_Submission of Personal Information_

You may register at our Site and provide personal information, at such times as when you download software, register new products, access product information, features or programs, or sign into a page that requires authorization. This may include your name, email address, physical address, credit card number, etc. You may also provide demographic information such as your education level, household income, and whether you are a personal or business user. You will know what you submit in each case, because you will manually enter the information. If you choose not to register and provide this information, you can still use most of the Site. Unfortunately, you will not be able to access areas that require registration.

_Children's Personal Information_

We do not knowingly collect personal information from users under the age of 13. If we are made aware that we have such personal information, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information.

_Automatic Collection of Information_

Logitech automatically collects on our server logs certain information about your computer hardware and software when you visit our Site. This information may include such things as your IP address, operating system, a description of any Logitech products connected and how such products are used, browser type, domain names, access times, service provider and referring website addresses.

Logitech and its third party service providers collect non-personal information about how you use our Site through cookies, Internet tags (e.g., web beacons) and other technologies in the aggregate, and track navigational data. We also collect information such as the URL of the website you previously visited, the pages you visit within our Site and any transaction details (downloads, requests, etc.). This information is used to understand how you interact with our Site, and help us optimize our marketing efforts including managing our advertising on other sites providing you ads based on your activities on our Site.

If you wish to manage your preference of being served target ads, you may click here. Please note that whatever your preference you will continue to receive non-personalized ads. You may also set your browser to notify you when a cookie is set or to refuse or delete cookies altogether, but certain features of our Site might not work.

_Social Media Features_

Our Site includes social network media features, such as the Facebook Like button, and widgets, including the Share button (collectively “Features”). These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. These features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site, and they allow you the ability to post information about your activities on this Site to your profile page to share with others within your network. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

_Single Sign-On_

You can log in to our Site by signing in with your social network login credential services such as Facebook or Linkedin. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook give you the option to post information about your activities on this Site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

_Purchase of Products_

Our shopping cart and checkout pages may have the look and feel of being on [www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/), however the payment information, including credit card information, that you submit on these pages is collected by our payment processor and not collected by Logitech. Our payment processor is authorized to collect and use the submitted information only for the purposes of providing this service.

We recommend you read the privacy statement of our payment processor, viewable where your information is collected.

Back to top

#### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

_Personal Information_

Logitech only uses your personal information for the purpose that you provide it to us (e.g., technical support when you provided information for that purpose). Logitech uses this information to communicate with you either via the Internet or e-mail. (The only exceptions to this Statement are “service and follow up e-mails” that may notify you about system downtimes, product problems or recalls, password reminder e-mails, and information after you have purchased a product.)

If you submit personal information to any third party websites linked to or from our Site, your information is governed by their privacy statement. Logitech encourages you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

_Use of non-Personal Information_

We also use anonymous and aggregated data to create statistics and reports for various business purposes. We may aggregate anonymous data and share the anonymous data with our co-marketing partners in order to offer all our customers potentially desirable products and services as well as to improve our content and services.

_E-Mail Messaging_

Logitech will periodically send users e-mail messages about our products and services. We also use tracking pixels to determine, in the aggregate, how many people open our e-mails.

_Safe Harbor and Disclosure of Information_

Personal information collected on this Site may be stored and processed in the United States or in any other country Logitech or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities. By using this Site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Logitech complies with the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Logitech has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Logitech’s certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

Logitech also complies with the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses for transfers from data controllers to data controllers and to data processors established outside the EU/EEA.

Logitech does not share, trade, rent, sell or otherwise disclose our customer or user information to unaffiliated companies. We disclose information you submit only as follows:

  * We hire affiliated and unaffiliated service providers to provide service to you including Logitech Inc., which are certified under the EU/CH-US Safe Harbor Program as set forth above and have entered into data processing agreements using EU Commissions’ standard contractual clauses. For example, we may use an email service provider to submit email communications to you on our behalf. All service providers are subject to strict confidentiality obligations and process your information only on our behalf and subject to our instructions.
  * We may share redacted or anonymized information freely, but only after we redact it to ensure that recipients cannot use the data to identify you or link the data to you.
  * We may have to disclose information for purposes of protecting your or our legal rights or as required by law or orders from courts and government entities.
  * We may disclose to another business entity should we plan to merge with or be acquired by that business entity; or to any organization involved in a merger, transfer, or sale of our assets or business.
  * Before we disclose your personal information for other reasons, we will first obtain your consent, for example via e-mail, click-through, an online opportunity to opt-out, or otherwise.
  * If you post any information in public areas of our Site, such as community forums, blog or other areas, it will be available to the public and we may reuse and republish such information at our discretion and in accordance with our Terms of Use.
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Logitech, including its Site.

In the event that we disclose your personal information as set out above, we will require third party organizations to protect and maintain your information in compliance with our policies.

_Prohibited Disclosures_

Except as set forth above, Logitech will not disclose your personal information to any third party, including advertisers, without your explicit consent.

Back to top  

#### CONTROL & REVIEW OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

You have the ability to direct us to update or delete/deactivate certain information pertaining to you by using any of the methods listed below:

Phone: +1 510-795-8500  
Contact: [support.logitech.com/response-center](http://support.logitech.com/response-center)  
Postal Mail: Logitech Privacy Officer, 7700 Gateway Blvd., Newark, CA 94560 USA

Web site: <http://www.logitech.com/subscribe>

You can also use these vehicles to request removal of your personal information from the blog, community forums or other public areas on our Site. Logitech may not be able to remove some or all of your personal information, in which case we will let you know why. You may stop the delivery of marketing e-mails by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in the email received or at the subscription management page on our Site. Logitech will respond to your request to review the information we have on file for you within 30 days from receiving such request.

We provide you the opportunity to “opt-out” of having your personal information used for certain purposes whenever we ask for this information. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements.

Back to top  

#### PROTECTION OF INFORMATION

Logitech is committed to the protection of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures, including SSL encryption, to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Site, [www.logitech.com](http://www.logitech.com/), and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the Site or from Alert.Logitech.com. In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe, please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Statement or practices, please contact us at [support.logitech.com/response-center](http://support.logitech.com/response-center). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request) or refer your privacy complaint or dispute to the relevant state or notational data protection authority in your jurisdiction.

Back to top  

#### CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT

Logitech will occasionally update this Statement. If there are material changes to this Statement or to how Logitech will use your personal information, Logitech will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. In any case we will not make any changes that are less protective of your personal information collected in the past without your consent.

Logitech encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Logitech is protecting your information.

Thank you for your interest in Logitech and our products.

Revised January 29, 2016

#### Cookies

Our site uses "cookies," small text files that can be read by a web server in the domain that put the cookie on your hard drive. Click here to learn more.
